## **Thukaram Rao Ambekar**

Solution Architect | +91 9591195577 | a.thukaram.rao@gmail.com

# Summary

Enterprise Solution Architect and Technology Manager with demonstrated working experience of **9** years' experience in retail, Banking and Telecom. Skilled in Integration, API Management, Solutioning Customer Facing Applications, Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), Management, and Requirements Analysis. Strong engineering professional with a master's in computer applications focused on Information Technology.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### JNTU - Anantapur

## Intell Engineering college, Anantapur

M. Tech in Computers Science & Engineering with 72%

Pass out in 2015

• Project & Published: 'A Novel Authentication Scheme for Multicast Traffic Ad-hoc Networks' paper at IJETCSE in February 2015.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Acuvate Solutions Hyderabad, INDIA

Technical Architect – 'Desert Financial Credit Union Bank'

May 2023 – Present

- Discovery of inefficiencies in Organization wide processes, It displays maps of clients processes with data and metrics to recognize performance issues.
- Working closely with Stakeholders to understand the business flow and iterative process along with application usage/interaction.
- **Using MS Power Automate**: with 'Process Advisor' feature we trace and identify multiple processes to identify the data mining, KPI's & ROI.
- Understand what business clients do while performing each task on their desktops, Identify & eliminate unnecessary actions in process tasks.
- Identify the most common actions through user/SME interactions, ensure compliance & perform audit, automate tasks that would accelerate processes and reduce human errors.

Acronotics Pvt Ltd Bengaluru, INDIA

Solution Consultant — 'Honeywell'

November 2022 – May 2023

- 10% development activities include assisting project management, leading work product reviews and mentoring / coaching / assisting project team members.
- Works with development team managers to develop a customer-specific Statement of Work (SoW) to be included in proposal.
- Works with Program Managers, Group Managers and assists in the development of the program roadmap. Working collaboratively with project managers, developers, and end-users to deliver working solutions.
- Analyzing migration complex & impediments of the process to run/execute in Automation Anywhere A360.

 Identifying the issues and giving solutions on migrated task to run in A360, preparing handbook for developers on key points. Have working experience on issue resolving in API, SAP & DB connection in migration process.

#### **Accenture Solutions Private Ltd**

Bengaluru, INDIA

Solution Architect – 'Bank Of America Corporation'

May 2020 to November 2022

- Presented roadmap & technology infrastructure to customers, demonstrating deep familiarity with APIs, platform infrastructure, security, and integration capabilities.
- Collaborating with multiple business leaders to develop integrated retail and omni-channel product roadmaps.
- Driven critical retail digital solutions end to end (Requirement gathering, Analysis, Design, Functional (HDD), QA, Deployment & implementation), Design Failure point to analyses failures and reprocess them successfully.
- Design Caching solution for faster throughput/response time, worked with customers or prospective customers to develop integrated solutions and lead detailed architectural dialogues to facilitate delivery of comprehensive solution.
- Implemented processes and procedures to improve overall efficiency in operations with Automation of CI/CD (Code Review and Deployments).
- Project planning with resource and financial estimates to align with IT portfolio.

Solution Consultant/Architect – 'British Petroleum'

May 2019 – April 2020

- As a Solution Designer, involved in various Solution design activities in multiple projects.
- Creation of Solution Design Document (SDD), Process walkthroughs and High level/low-level sessions with client and project teams.
- Designing Solution Design Document, Technical Design Document, and Business Continuity Plan making clear to business owner & team members adding with all necessary group approvals and reference notes.
- Estimated automation benefit of \$220 K/15 FTE Entails the process of 'Cardinal Health R2PRO Automation'.
- Prepare and present project overview and maintain regular project status updates to Accenture leadership through Azure ADO board.
- Have been proactive in getting various issues resolved (Technical, Infrastructure, Business requirement clarifications, opportunities deliver management etc.)
- Honor to receive client appreciation from BP Automation.

#### LTI - Larsen & Toubro Infotech

Bengaluru, INDIA

Developer Lead (RPA) – 'Citi Bank & Société Générale'

February 2017 – April 2019

- Analyzed financial estimates, business summary reports and dashboard recaps to attain data based on Volume comparable AHT, KPI and implemented Bot to automate end to end business productivity.
- We developed Bot for processing business operations on Web Page, Citrix by Meta bots and performed Excel Operations on downloaded data, Bot executed the monarch operations and formats Excel data into MS Access database.

## **HP – (Hewlett-Packard)** as contract

Bengaluru, INDIA

Sr. Software Engineer

November 2016 – January 2017

 Worked as Test analyst: writing test scripts and executing test cases, identifying bugs, raise ticket in JERA tool. Submitting test matrix to Sr Leads on daily as reports. Updating work progress to Project Lead on weekly status call.

#### MINACS IT Services as contract

Bengaluru, INDIA

**Software Engineer** 

November 2015 - September 2016

- Involving in SDTLC and Business analysis to understand and create test scripts with traceability matrix attaining smoke test on application/component deployment in production with new version.
- Using JERA tool, raising tickets on negative test case. Waiting for workaround to continue next test scenarios and complete component testing for that sprint.

IBM as contract

Bengaluru, INDIA

Software Test Engineer – 'AT&T'

April 2014 – August 2015

- AT&T is a telecom company with multiple plans and packages to provide & improve subscribers across the globe. Telecom bill plan data details generated in Mainframe & extracting data loading into SQL DB Tables.
- Working on ETL tools, generating daily and weekly test execution reports. Updating the test scenarios and involved in SIT testing at migration/deployment time.

## **LEADERSHIP & ACTIVITIES**

# **Solution Architect/Consultant**

May 2019 – November 2022

- Achieving IT goals by creating vision and leading teams through project challenges. Managing third-party vendors including selection, negotiation, and relationship management.
- Providing enterprise architecture oversight to team efforts below.
- Conduct market research and provide high-level capabilities, solution approach (Build / Buy decision) and costing (mostly through leveraging industry & technology research & RFI/RFP/RFQ process).
- Team Lead call out the impediments from each developer and provide solutions interacting with Business SME/AA Team in daily stand-up meetings.
- Effectively driving Delivery of Critical, High visibility and Time bound Projects.
- Achieving the target to complete migration process with team sprite and proved our strength to clients with teamwork – Team management skills.
- understanding their requirements, managing their demand, and delivering an economically well-assessed solution to the business problem in a timely manner.
- Performing Technical assessment to analyze the business feasibility, volume of data, In-scope and identifying criticality of business process.

### **RPA Development** 'Automation Anywhere Tool'

February 2017 - April 2019

- Co-ordinating with business SME to understand process and implement validations, exceptions, notifications, and Log files creations.
- Deploying tasks from Dev to Production, adding Bot NTID and passwords into Control room credential vault. Creating a pool for multiple VM's and auto scheduling Bot orchestrator.

### **HONORS & AWARDS**

- Received certificate of excellence Award for BP automation project delivery.
- Received Business client appreciation on delivering projects on time.
- Achieved and recognized in Deliver Solution design & Costing for the EA COE.
- Partaking into Origination events like Sports & Cultural activists.

# **Area of Expertise**

- Leadership
- Team Management
- IT Governance & Technical Implementation
- Capital Budget Management
- System Integration
- JavaScript
- SaaS (like AWS, Azure)

- Technical Architecture
- Disaster Recovery Planning
- API Management
- B2B Applications
- Strategic IT Planning
- RPA (A11, A360 with certification, UiPath)
- SCRUM master